## Luis Gabriel Gómez

Buenos Aires - Birthdate: 11/26/1990 Email: luis.gg1990 [at] gmail.com

Personal Site - GitHub - LinkedIn

## Education

2009 - 2013: Universidad Nacional de San Martín

Technicature in Computer Programming (Incomplete)

2014 - 2019: Universidad CAECE

Bachelor's Degree in Information Systems (Incomplete)

2020 - (In Progress) Universidad de Palermo

Bachelor's Degree in Electronics Engineering

# Languages

Portuguese: Basic

English: Advanced proficiency

**Spanish:** Native speaker

# Summary

Backend and web developer (currently working on distributed backend systems), with a focus on research and development on the implementation of solutions, providing training and assistance to new team recruits and trainees, and giving extensive support to the clients, collaborating directly with their development personnel when needed. Open source contributor

### Personal objectives:

- Acquire new and cutting edge knowledge about software design and architecture
- Acquire new knowledge and broaden the existing one about the internals of the platforms I'm working with
- Continue growing as a professional developer, with a strong focus on the technical side
- Expand my skills and knowledge towards other technological stacks
- Conduct analysis of open source projects for their use in work related solutions and contribute back if possible

# Work Experience

### MuleSoft

## Lead Member of Technical Staff (LMTS) - Backend Jun 2021 - today

Worked on several maintenance and new features for one of Mulesoft's management services, as an individual contributor and with the team. Participation in cross-team requirements and giving technical guidance and/or assistance. Research of existing implementation limitations and iterations to adapt to new requirements, and implementations of required technologies. Some of the mainly involved ones:

- Java (JGSS, JAAS)
- Kerberos V5 (Heimdal and MIT flavors)
- Scripting: Python, shell
- FreeIPA (basic)
- AWS: EC2, Terraform among others

### **Pedidos Ya**

## Principal Software Engineer - Backend Jun 2021 - today

Design and implementation of a distributed static geospatial data store as a service in golang, along with related tooling and support on core backend libraries for the backend tribe

# Santander Tecnología

Technical Leader - Systems Architecture

### Apr 2021 - Jun 2021

Continuation of the previously mentioned tasks with a strong focus on the asistance of architecture design of new APIs and technical leadership of the implementing teams, along with technical governance tasks such as contract reviews and internal technical standards development (API, architecture and development guidelines)

# Senior+ Software Engineer - APICore and Architecture teams May 2020 - Apr 2021

Design, implementation and developer support of core infrastructure and API features, including (but not limited) to:

- Entire golang technology stack:
  - Restful API development framework
  - Infrastructure and CI support (pipeline, docker images)
  - o Defining project templating and scaffolding
  - Development and support of first POC API projects serving core business and internal IT initiatives
- Involvement in the design process of greenfield services, and how these must operate with legacy services, including development guidelines
- Giving training and consultancy to the IT/delivery teams in the form of brown bag or architecture/technology talks

### Mercado Libre

#### Software Engineer - Mercado Pago Core Services: September 2019 - May 2020

Design and implementation in golang of distributed systems and mission-critical components, in the scope of the core backend services and for payment processing in Mercado Pago, including core libraries for associated teams

### Software Engineer: June 2017 - September 2019

Backend development in distributed systems belonging to our shipping network infrastructure. Tasks include:

- Analysis of existing mission-critical components in grails
- Redesign and re-implementation of backend systems in golang
- Research and development of solutions for scalability of legacy and new services
- Transfer knowledge to new team members and design of technical guidelines on the team level
- Research and troubleshooting of performance and scalability incidents
- Continuous iteration of core frameworks used cross-team

### Hexacta

### Senior .NET Developer: January 2016 – June 2017

Frontend and backend development in internal and business critical systems for our client in the banking business (credit card emitter)

- Analysis of complex business requirements
- Design and implementation of solutions for both greenfield and brownfield systems
- Coaching and training to junior and semi senior developers on C# and .NET, with focus on advanced topics
- Support and triage on technical issues of high criticality
- I traveled to the client's HQ in USA in order to work alongside their developers when designing new solutions and working on legacy systems
- Development of custom tools and scripts to be used by our teams, improving development times
- Technologies used: C# versions 2, 5 and 6 (.NET Framework 2.0 to 4.6). ADO.NET. Winforms.
  Unity IoC, Automapper 4. ASP.NET MVC 4. JQuery 1.8+, Angular 1.4. Powershell, batch.
  Javascript. Oracle 11g
- Methodologies used: Scrum, Kanban, Waterfall

## Globallogic

### Software Developer: February 2013 - December 2015

Backend and frontend development, serving as an acting maintainer of architecture components on both sides

- Development of custom tools and scripts to be used by our development teams, improving development times
- Migration of complex business critical systems for an important insurance client
- Coaching and training of new recruits in C# y .NET
- Technical support to the client on complex issues
- Onsite support to the client
- Technologies used: C# 5 (.NET Framework 4.5). WCF. ADO.NET. NHibernate 2, Automapper 3.
  ASP.NET MVC 4. JQuery 1.8, Knockout 2.2, Underscore 1.4.4. Bootstrap 2. Javascript, Typescript versions 0.8 and 1.4. SQL Server 2012
- Methodologies used: Scrum, XP

### Freelance

Web Developer: October 2012 – January 2013

- Assistance and support in the development of a billing system for a medical insurer services contractor
- Technologies used: PHP 5, JQuery 1.4, MySQL

### Personal work (current and previous)

- Angular 1.4
- Typescript
- SQLite 3, Entity Framework 6
- WPF
- WinAPI (via P/Invoke in .NET), Visual Studio SDK (extensions)
- Golang
- Arduino (beginner)

# Personal profile

I consider myself an enthusiast of technology. I'm currently working as a backend developer, with a strong background in the .NET platform but currently specializing in golang. I'm always open to try new and alternative stacks, with a continued interest in following the latest advances in application development technologies.

My main aspirations are the following:

- Working on systems with high performance and/or scalability requirements, aside from giving support to existing or ordinary systems with performance issues
- Develop state-of-the art solutions through research and collaboration between high-performance teams
- Strive for a continued use of best practices and transmit that knowledge to fellow team members accordingly
- Maintain and boost the morale of the team through collaboration, debate, and fun